Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Kathryn and we have an unusual lesson for you today.
我是Kathryn，今天我们有一节不同寻常的课程。
It's more about writing than about speaking.
这节课更多是关于写作，而不是口语。
That's right.
没错。
Well, many times we have to write emails and if we're working in a sales environment, we
嗯，很多时候我们都需要写邮件，如果我们在销售环境中工作，
may need to write an email to a potential client.
可能需要给潜在客户写一封邮件。
Alright, so we're going to learn what is appropriate and what is not in today's lesson.
好的，所以在今天的课程中，我们将学习什么是合适的，什么是不合适的。
Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
让我们来听一下我们的对话。
Melanie, can you help me with something?
Melanie，你能帮我个忙吗？
We need to finalize the account with the Mexican embassy and I need some advice on phrasing
我们需要敲定与墨西哥大使馆的账户，我需要一些关于如何用英语正确措辞这封信的建议。
this letter correctly in English.
这封信。
Sure Tracy, let me just get my laptop.
当然，Tracy，让我拿一下我的笔记本电脑。
Right, all set.
好了，准备好了。
Ok, so, to whom it may concern, I am writing…
好的，那么，敬启者，我写信是为了……
Um, Tracy, I think that's a little too formal.
嗯，Tracy，我觉得这有点太正式了。
I know you want to be polite, but you've already made contact with them, so in English,
我知道你想表现得礼貌，但你已经和他们联系过了，所以在英语中，
you can be a bit more relaxed in the opening.
开头可以稍微放松一点。
Ok, more relaxed.
好的，更放松一点。
Got it.
明白了。
Hey Sally, what's up?
嘿，Sally，最近怎么样？
It's Tracy here, just…
我是Tracy，只是……
Ok, Tracy, now it's too relaxed.
好了，Tracy，现在又太随意了。
You've still got to show some respect.
你还是得表现出一些尊重。
How about starting with Dear Miss Cooper, I'm writing to confirm…
不如以“亲爱的Cooper小姐，我写信是为了确认……”开头？
Great, ok.
太好了，好的。
Dear Miss Cooper, I'm writing to confirm the final quotation for the full-page back
亲爱的Cooper小姐，我写信是为了确认您为《Viola》杂志春季刊要求的全页封底彩色广告的最终报价。
cover color advertisement you requested for the spring issue of Viola Magazine.
全页封底彩色广告。
That's great.
太好了。
The final costing, including advert design and production, comes to 45,600 RMB.
最终成本，包括广告设计和制作，共计45,600元人民币。
We want payment 10 working days before publication, or we will cancel the ad.
我们要求在出版前10个工作日付款，否则我们将取消广告。
Thanks for…
感谢……
Whoa, ok, back up a second Tracy.
哇，好的，Tracy，先停一下。
That's too direct.
这太直接了。
Can I suggest you say, please note that the final payment is due two working weeks before
我建议你说，请注意，最终付款应在出版前两个工作周内支付。
publication.
支付。
You don't want to offend her.
你不想冒犯她。
Oops, ok, you're right.
哎呀，好的，你说得对。
Then I can just end with, all the best, Tracy.
那我就可以以“此致敬礼，Tracy”结尾。
Hmm, maybe I'd play it safe and just finish with, yours sincerely.
嗯，也许我会稳妥一点，就以“您真诚的”结尾。
That's more professional.
那样更专业。
Oh, Melanie, you're a lifesaver.
哦，Melanie，你真是我的救星。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Alright, we're back, so now let's take a look at some of that vocab we heard on
好了，我们回来了，现在让我们看看在“语言要点”中听到的一些词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
We have some wonderful adjectives today.
今天我们有一些很棒的形容词。
The first one that I wanted to discuss, Marco, is formal.
我想讨论的第一个词，Marco，是“正式”。
Formal, that's right.
“正式”，没错。
We want to be a little bit more formal when we're writing someone we don't really know
当我们给不太熟悉的人写信时，我们想表现得稍微正式一点。
too much.
不太熟悉的人。
That's right.
没错。
But be careful because sometimes you can be too formal.
但要小心，因为有时你可能太正式了。
So what exactly does formal mean?
那么“正式”到底是什么意思呢？
So if you write a formal email, it's very proper, very respectful.
如果你写一封正式的邮件，它非常得体，非常尊重。
So proper in the way that you wouldn't use colloquial terms or phrasal verbs that you
得体是指你不会使用和朋友们说话时用的口语化词汇或短语动词。
would use with your friends.
口语化词汇或短语动词。
No, a good example is writing to a lawyer or a judge.
不，一个很好的例子是给律师或法官写信。
You want to use formal language.
你想使用正式的语言。
Even with a teacher, you might use more formal language.
即使是对老师，你也可能使用更正式的语言。
But with a friend, you don't have to.
但对朋友，你就不必这样。
That's something else.
那是另一回事。
That's right.
没错。
So when you're writing something that's formal, it's important to be polite as well.
所以当你写正式的东西时，保持礼貌也很重要。
Now what is polite?
那么什么是“礼貌”呢？
Right.
对。
So you want to be formal, you want to be serious, and you want to be polite.
所以你想表现得正式、严肃，并且想表现得礼貌。
You want to show respect.
你想表现出尊重。
You want to be nice, basically.
基本上，你想表现得友善。
That's right.
没错。
And so people can often be described as polite.
人们经常可以被描述为有礼貌。
He's very polite or she's not polite at all.
他很有礼貌，或者她一点也不礼貌。
And when I was a little kid, my mom used to say, it's very important to be polite.
我小时候，我妈妈常说，有礼貌非常重要。
You say thank you and you're welcome when you're talking to other people.
和别人说话时要说“谢谢”和“不客气”。
That's right.
没错。
And that's one way of being polite.
这是有礼貌的一种方式。
Now also when we are describing the way that you speak to someone or the way that you write,
另外，当我们描述你说话或写作的方式时，
you can be very direct.
你可以非常“直接”。
Now being direct means that you say exactly what you want or exactly what you're thinking.
“直接”意味着你准确地说出你想要什么或你在想什么。
Okay, so maybe if we're talking to this company, you say, hi, I want this.
好的，所以如果我们和这家公司谈话，你说，嗨，我想要这个。
I will pay this much.
我会付这么多钱。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Bye.
再见。
Right.
对。
That's maybe too direct.
那可能太直接了。
You need to be a little less direct and say nice things in an email.
你需要稍微委婉一点，在邮件里说些好话。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe you want to say to someone that you don't really like the clothes they're wearing,
所以，比如你想对某人说，你不太喜欢他们穿的衣服，
right?
对吧？
You say, hey, do you like my new shirt?
你说，嘿，你喜欢我的新衬衫吗？
And if you're very direct, you would say, no, I think it's very ugly.
如果你很直接，你会说，不，我觉得它很丑。
I hate it.
我讨厌它。
Right.
对。
That's too direct.
那太直接了。
So maybe you would say, I don't really think it suits you very well.
所以也许你会说，我不太觉得它很适合你。
Or I think a different color would be better on you.
或者，我觉得换个颜色会更好看。
That's right.
没错。
So that's being a little bit less direct.
所以这就是稍微委婉一点。
Now obviously, if you're too direct with someone, you may offend that person.
现在，显然，如果你对某人太直接，你可能会冒犯到那个人。
Alright, to offend is a verb and to offend someone means to say something that makes
好的，“冒犯”是一个动词，冒犯某人意味着说一些让他们
them unhappy or upset or even angry.
不开心、难过甚至生气的话。
So going back to the same example of the shirt, if you say, I think that shirt is very ugly,
所以回到衬衫的例子，如果你说，我觉得那件衬衫很丑，
that person might be offended.
那个人可能会被冒犯。
Gosh.
天哪。
Or maybe if you say, I think people with brown hair are so ugly and there's someone next
或者，如果你说，我觉得棕色头发的人很丑，而旁边
to me with brown hair, they say, oh, I'm offended.
就有一个棕色头发的人，他们会说，哦，我被冒犯了。
Right.
对。
I'm not ugly, but I have brown hair.
我不丑，但我有棕色头发。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so you don't want to offend anyone by being too direct or you don't want to have
好的，所以你不想因为太直接而冒犯任何人，或者你不想让
anyone feel offended.
任何人感到被冒犯。
Now for our last phrase here on Language Takeaway, we have towards the end of the dialogue, Tracy
现在，在“语言小贴士”的最后一个短语中，在对话的结尾，Tracy
thanks Melanie by saying, you are a lifesaver.
感谢Melanie时说，“你真是我的救星。”
Thank you.
谢谢。
Okay, so don't be confused.
好的，所以别搞混了。
There is also a candy called lifesavers and she's not calling her a candy.
还有一种糖果叫“救生圈”，她不是在叫她糖果。
She's saying, wow, thank you.
她说的是，哇，谢谢你。
You really helped me.
你真的帮了我大忙。
So when someone helps you a lot, you can call them a lifesaver.
所以当有人帮了你大忙时，你可以叫他们“救星”。
Marco, what exactly is the object, the lifesaver?
Marco，“救星”这个东西到底是什么？
If you've ever been on a boat, you see this big orange circle that is used to throw into
如果你坐过船，你会看到那个用来扔进
the water to help someone to prevent them from drowning.
水里帮助别人防止溺水的大橙色圆圈。
That is called a lifesaver.
那东西就叫“救生圈”。
Okay, so I'm drowning.
好的，所以我快淹死了。
I'm having a hard time writing this email.
我写这封邮件很费劲。
I do not know what to say.
我不知道该说什么。
Marco, you come and help me.
Marco，你来帮我。
I can say, oh wow, thank you so much.
我可以说，哦哇，太感谢你了。
You're a lifesaver.
你真是我的救星。
That's exactly right.
完全正确。
All right, so we've taken a look at five key words there.
好了，我们看了五个关键词。
Why don't we take a listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
我们再来听一遍对话，然后回来讲“流利度训练”。
Melanie, can you help me with something?
Melanie，你能帮我个忙吗？
We need to finalize the account with the Mexican embassy and I need some advice on phrasing
我们需要敲定与墨西哥大使馆的账目，我需要一些关于如何用英语
this letter correctly in English.
正确措辞这封信的建议。
Sure Tracy, let me just get my laptop.
当然Tracy，让我拿一下我的笔记本电脑。
Right, all set.
好了，准备好了。
Okay, so to whom it may concern, I am writing...
好的，那么“敬启者，我写信是为了……”
Tracy, I think that's a little too formal.
Tracy，我觉得那有点太正式了。
I know you want to be polite, but you've already made contact with them, so in English, you
我知道你想礼貌，但你已经和他们联系过了，所以在英语里，你
can be a bit more relaxed in the opening.
可以在开头稍微放松一点。
Okay, more relaxed.
好的，放松一点。
Got it.
明白了。
Hey Sally, what's up?
嘿Sally，最近怎么样？
It's Tracy here, just...
我是Tracy，只是……
Okay Tracy, now it's too relaxed.
好了Tracy，现在又太随意了。
You've still got to show some respect.
你还是得表现出一些尊重。
How about starting with, dear Miss Cooper, I'm writing to confirm...
以“亲爱的Cooper小姐，我写信是为了确认……”开头怎么样？
Great, okay.
太好了，好的。
Dear Miss Cooper, I'm writing to confirm the final quotation for the full-page back cover
亲爱的Cooper小姐，我写信是为了确认您为《Viola》杂志春季刊
color advertisement you requested for the spring issue of Viola Magazine.
要求的全页封底彩色广告的最终报价。
That's great.
太好了。
The final costing, including advert design and production, comes to 45,600 RMB.
最终成本，包括广告设计和制作，是45,600元人民币。
We want payment 10 working days before publication, or we will cancel the ad.
我们要求在出版前10个工作日付款，否则我们将取消广告。
Thanks for...
感谢……
Whoa, okay, back up a second Tracy.
哇，好了，先停一下Tracy。
That's too direct.
那太直接了。
Can I suggest you say, please note that the final payment is due two working weeks before
我建议你说，“请注意，最终付款应在出版前两个工作周
publication.
内支付。”
You don't want to offend her.
你不想冒犯她。
Oops, okay, you're right.
哎呀，好吧，你说得对。
Then I can just end with, all the best, Tracy.
那我就可以用“此致敬礼，特蕾西”来结尾了。
Maybe I'd play it safe and just finish with, yours sincerely.
也许我会稳妥一点，就用“你真诚的”来结束。
That's more professional.
那样更专业。
Oh, Melanie, you're a lifesaver.
哦，梅兰妮，你真是救星。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
So today in Fluency Builder we have a number of phrases you can use when you're writing
所以在今天的流利度训练中，我们有一些短语，你可以在写
an email.
邮件时使用。
Some of them are very polite and formal.
其中一些非常礼貌和正式。
Some of them are very informal or casual.
还有一些非常非正式或随意。
Now this first phrase, Marco, is very, very formal, right?
现在第一个短语，马可，非常非常正式，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
You start the letter by stating, to whom it may concern.
你开始写信时要说“敬启者”。
All right, to whom it may concern.
好的，“敬启者”。
Remember that M there.
记住那个M要大写。
This is a very formal phrase and we're going to take it as a phrase.
这是一个非常正式的短语，我们把它当作一个固定短语。
This is how you begin a formal letter.
这是开始一封正式信函的方式。
That's right.
没错。
Usually you start this letter if it's directed to maybe a company or someone not specific.
通常，如果这封信是写给一家公司或某个不特定的人，你会这样开头。
You don't know that person's name and you're just saying, you know, whoever's reading this
你不知道那个人的名字，你只是说，你知道的，任何读到这封
letter, whoever it concerns.
信的人，任何相关的人。
That's right.
没错。
Well, I could say, dear Marco, but in this case, maybe I don't know who the name of the
嗯，我可以说“亲爱的马可”，但在这个情况下，也许我不知道我写这封邮件给
person I am writing this email to.
的人的名字。
It's a big company.
这是一家大公司。
There are many people.
有很多人。
So if you don't know who you're writing to in a company or in an organization, you say,
所以如果你不知道你在公司或组织里写给谁，你就说
to whom it may concern.
“敬启者”。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Now we started very formal.
现在我们开始得很正式。
Melanie said, I think it's a little bit too formal.
梅兰妮说，我觉得有点太正式了。
Maybe we should be more relaxed.
也许我们应该更放松一点。
So Tracy says, okay, got it.
所以特蕾西说，好的，明白了。
So how about, hey Sally, what's up?
那“嘿，莎莉，怎么了？”怎么样？
What's up?
怎么了？
Okay.
好的。
So what's up is the kind of thing I say with my friends, you know, hey Marco, what's up?
所以“怎么了”是我和朋友说的那种话，你知道的，“嘿，马可，怎么了？”
Right.
对。
But I would never say this in a formal situation with a boss or with a, you know, an employer
但我绝不会在正式场合对老板或雇主说这个，或者，嗯，在更严肃的
or with a, um, in more serious situation.
情况下。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Especially if you're writing a, an email to a client, you don't really want to say what's
特别是如果你在给客户写邮件，你真的不想说“怎么了”。
up.
绝不。
No, never.
不，永远不会。
So remember this is spoken English with your friends, but not something you would write.
所以记住这是和朋友说的口语英语，但不是你会写下来的东西。
Um, so the key here is that you have to show some respect.
嗯，所以关键是你必须表现出一些尊重。
Okay.
好的。
So that's another great phrase, you show some respect.
所以那是另一个很好的短语，你表现出一些尊重。
All right.
好的。
So the key here is that this is, um, the verb is to show, right?
所以关键是这个，嗯，动词是“表现”，对吧？
Not to give.
不是“给予”。
Um, you want to show respect to someone.
嗯，你想对某人表现出尊重。
Well, how do you show respect?
嗯，你怎么表现出尊重？
Well, the way that you act, your behaviors.
嗯，通过你的行为方式，你的举止。
So if I'm polite and I say, you know, Mr. and Miss and thank you and please, these are
所以如果我有礼貌，我说，你知道的，“先生”和“女士”以及“谢谢”和“请”，这些是
ways to show respect.
表现出尊重的方式。
That's right.
没错。
So that's the way that you are being respectful.
所以那就是你表示尊重的方式。
You are showing respect by being very polite.
你通过非常有礼貌来表现出尊重。
For example, in Japan, it is common to take your shoes off when you go to a friend's home,
例如，在日本，当你去朋友家时，脱鞋是常见的，
their house in order to show respect to them.
以表示对他们的尊重。
That's right.
没错。
Very good.
非常好。
Now, as we continue writing the letter towards the end, we wanted to play it safe and just
现在，当我们继续写信到结尾时，我们想稳妥一点，就
write your sincerely to close the letter off.
写“你真诚的”来结束这封信。
All right.
好的。
So this phrase, play it safe.
所以这个短语，“稳妥一点”。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
When we're talking about making a decision or taking a risk, we want to play it safe.
当我们谈论做决定或冒险时，我们想稳妥一点。
We want to use the less risky option.
我们想用风险较小的选项。
All right.
好的。
So the key here is that the verb is to play.
所以关键是动词是“玩”。
Play it safe.
稳妥一点。
This means that, yeah, there's maybe a risky option and a safe option and it's better to
这意味着，是的，也许有一个冒险的选项和一个安全的选项，最好
take the safe option.
选择安全的选项。
Play it safe.
稳妥一点。
That's right.
没错。
So that's the way that you would use this phrase to play it safe, to make a decision
所以这就是你使用这个短语的方式，以求稳妥，做出一个决定
that doesn't have too much risk or that you know that will work very well.
风险不大或者你知道会很顺利的决定。
And to close things off, another option to end the letter, we could say, all the best.
最后，结束信件的另一种选择，我们可以说，一切顺利。
All the best, Tracy.
一切顺利，特蕾西。
All right.
好了。
So this is a way to end a letter.
所以这是结束一封信的一种方式。
You can say sincerely or best, but it's a very nice way to end if you just say all the
你可以说“此致敬礼”或“祝好”，但如果你只说“一切顺利”，这是一种很好的结束方式
best and then you say, you know, after that you have a comma and then you sign your name.
然后，你知道，后面加个逗号，再签上你的名字。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好了。
Let's listen to our dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
让我们最后听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一会儿。
Melanie, can you help me with something?
梅兰妮，你能帮我个忙吗？
We need to finalize the account with the Mexican embassy and I need some advice on phrasing
我们需要敲定与墨西哥大使馆的账目，我需要一些关于如何用英语正确措辞这封信的建议。
this letter correctly in English.
这封信。
Sure, Tracy.
当然，特蕾西。
Let me just get my laptop.
让我拿一下我的笔记本电脑。
Right.
好的。
All set.
准备好了。
Okay, so to whom it may concern, I am writing...
好的，那么“敬启者，我写信是为了……”
Tracy, I think that's a little too formal.
特蕾西，我觉得那有点太正式了。
I know you want to be polite, but you've already made contact with them.
我知道你想有礼貌，但你已经和他们联系过了。
So in English, you can be a bit more relaxed in the opening.
所以在英语中，开头可以稍微放松一些。
Okay, more relaxed.
好的，更放松一些。
Got it.
明白了。
Hey, Sally, what's up?
嘿，莎莉，怎么了？
It's Tracy here.
我是特蕾西。
Just...
只是……
Okay, Tracy.
好了，特蕾西。
Now it's too relaxed.
现在又太随意了。
You've still got to show some respect.
你还是得表现出一些尊重。
How about starting with Dear Miss Cooper, I'm writing to confirm...
不如以“亲爱的库珀小姐，我写信是为了确认……”开头。
Great.
太好了。
Okay.
好的。
Dear Miss Cooper, I'm writing to confirm the final quotation for the full page back cover
亲爱的库珀小姐，我写信是为了确认您为《维奥拉杂志》春季刊要求的全页封底彩色广告的最终报价。
color advertisement you requested for the spring issue of Viola Magazine.
彩色广告。
That's great.
太好了。
The final costing, including advert design and production, comes to 45,600 RMB.
最终成本，包括广告设计和制作，共计45,600元人民币。
We want payment 10 working days before publication, or we will cancel the ad.
我们要求在出版前10个工作日付款，否则我们将取消广告。
Thanks for...
感谢……
Whoa.
哇。
Okay, back up a second, Tracy.
好的，特蕾西，退一步说。
That's too direct.
那太直接了。
Can I suggest you say, please note that the final payment is due two working weeks before
我建议你说，“请注意，最终付款应在出版前两个工作周内支付。”
publication.
出版前。
You don't want to offend her.
你不想冒犯她。
Oops.
哎呀。
Okay, you're right.
好的，你说得对。
Then I can just end with, all the best, Tracy.
那我就可以用“一切顺利，特蕾西”来结尾。
Maybe I'd play it safe and just finish with, yours sincerely.
也许我会稳妥一点，就用“此致敬礼”结尾。
That's more professional.
那样更专业。
Oh, Melanie, you're a lifesaver.
哦，梅兰妮，你真是救星。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
So talking about ending formal emails or emails that you're writing to clients, colleagues,
所以说到结束正式邮件或写给客户、同事的邮件，
we can say sincerely, and your name, sincerely, Marco.
我们可以说“此致敬礼”，然后是你的名字，“此致敬礼，马可”。
You can say, all the best, best regards.
你可以说“一切顺利”、“此致敬礼”。
Now I've noticed that some people who aren't native English speakers, sometimes they will
我注意到一些非英语母语者，有时他们会
close a letter, maybe even a formal letter, saying, yours truly, Marco, for example.
在信末，甚至正式信件，写上“你的真诚的，马可”之类的。
Is that really appropriate for a business setting or a client?
这在商务场合或对客户真的合适吗？
I would not use yours truly.
我不会用“你的真诚的”。
Maybe if you're trying to build a relationship with your client and you're very honest, but
也许如果你想和客户建立关系，而且你很坦诚，但
it seems to me to be very personal.
在我看来这太私人了。
Very romantic.
非常浪漫。
Yes, yours truly.
是的，“你的真诚的”。
So I would say in that case, use sincerely or kind regards, or regards, which are a little
所以在这种情况下，我会说用“此致敬礼”或“亲切问候”，或者“问候”，这些
bit more professional and less emotional.
更专业，情感色彩更少。
If you want to have a romantic letter, you can say, all my love or love or yours truly
如果你想写一封浪漫的信，你可以说“我所有的爱”或“爱你的”或“你的真诚的”
or yours faithfully.
或“你忠实的”。
This is a very important topic, I think, because many times in school we do learn how to write
我认为这是一个非常重要的话题，因为很多时候在学校里我们确实学过如何写
letters, but usually they are more personal letters.
信，但通常都是更私人的信件。
And so we memorize that usually at the end of the email or the end of the letter, you
所以我们记住了，通常在邮件或信件的结尾，你
say yours, Marco, or yours truly, Marco.
会说“你的，马可”或“你的真诚的，马可”。
And although it is correct, it's not really appropriate for a professional setting.
虽然这是正确的，但在专业场合并不合适。
That's right.
没错。
Just a reminder, if you're signing off your email or your letter and you're at an office,
提醒一下，如果你在结束邮件或信件时，你在办公室，
you're in your company, you want to say best or best regards or some of the things that
你在公司里，你想说“祝好”或“此致敬礼”或者我们今天讨论的一些
we talked about here today.
其他表达。
Very good.
非常好。
All right.
好了。
So if you have any questions or any other doubts, you can always find us at EnglishPod.com
所以如果你有任何问题或其他疑问，你随时可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
and we'll see you guys there.
我们到时候见。
Bye.
再见。
Bye-bye.
拜拜。